<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jerónimo Carranza Carranza on Jerónimo Carranza Carranza</title>
    <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jerónimo Carranza Carranza on Jerónimo Carranza Carranza</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Jerónimo Carranza Carranza</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>PROVISION OF INFORMATION ON SEVERAL STATISTICAL ACTIVITIES OF P.E.C.A. 2013- 2020. Lot 3. Databases of registrations of Andalusian Companies, December 2018 / January 2021.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2022-bormes-ieca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2022-bormes-ieca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Position&lt;/em&gt;: Head of project.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Recipients&lt;/em&gt;: Institute of Statistics and Cartography of Andalusia. 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work carried out has consisted in summary of the provision in electronic format, in databases, of the registry acts related to the constitution, increase and reduction of capital, disbursement of passive dividends, transformation, split, merger, dissolution, extinction and different phases bankruptcy of Andalusian commercial companies published in the Official Gazette of the Mercantile Registry (BORME), as well as the CIF and CNAE of said entities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To carry out these works, a set of automation routines have been developed for the download, reading, transformation, enrichment and data validation processes developed using the R programming language and SQLite as a support database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The processed data has fed the official Statistics on Andalusian Mercantile Companies between December 2018 and March 2022.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/2022-Borme-Ieca.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer technical assistance for the creation of a open spatial database to store and manage the data compiled in the catalog of hydraulic sanitation infrastructures of the Comunidad Valenciana.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2022-saneacv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2022-saneacv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Position&lt;/em&gt;: Head of project.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Recipients&lt;/em&gt;: TYPSA for the Department of Agriculture, Rural Development, Climate Emergencies and Ecological Transition. Government of Valencia. 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The works carried out have consisted schematically of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Definition and implementation of the data model of the Catalog of Hydraulic Infrastructures for Sanitation of the Valencian Community as a Postgresql / Postgis database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementation of the model, in tests, as an alternative or exchange, in SQLite / Geopackage database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download of geospatial and alphanumeric EIEL data, processing and loading of data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration of EIEL municipal data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ingestion and integration of information from municipalities and management organizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementation, loading and integration of geospatial and alphanumeric sanitation data from EPSAR, DGA, Global Omnium and other sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloading of data from administrative divisions, populations and nuclei of the CNIG, loading, integration and debugging of geospatial data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of QGIS base project for visualization and consultation of data available in the database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design and implementation of data mining queries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebGIS application. Deployment, adaptation, customization and start-up of a WebGIS application with access control for consultation, alphanumeric editing and validation by the municipalities of the information collected from the sanitation infrastructures of each one of them. It has also had access enabled for the CHJ and the Diputación de Castellón.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebGIS application maintenance for 14 months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/2022-Saneacv-0.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/2022-Saneacv-1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration of hydrological tools in GIS environment.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2022-chgn-migracion-hhgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2022-chgn-migracion-hhgis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Position&lt;/em&gt;: Head of project.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Recipients&lt;/em&gt;: Guadiana River Basin Authority. 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work carried out corresponds to the migration of various hydro-meteorological tools available to the Guadiana River Basin Authority, developed for ArcGIS, to the open Geographic Information System QGIS, using the Python programming language. Specifically, the following geoprocessing scripts have been developed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watershed analysis. Selection of masses (or sub-basins) upstream/downstream.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hydrological sense analysis. Selection of stretches of watercourses, upstream/downstream.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribution basin analysis. Calculation of inflow basins at selected points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIMPA data extraction. Given a layer of polygons, the calculation of accumulated values ​​for the different polygons is carried out based on the variables of the SIMPA model of CEDEX. The application allows you to select the range of hydrological years (1940-2018) for which the calculation is made. The result is a set of (non-geometric) tables that are stored in a geopackage (gpkg) file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/2022_CHGN_Migracion_HHGIS_captura.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementation of improvements in the prediction model of atmospheric phenomena of HELVETIA.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2021-helvetia-aemet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2021-helvetia-aemet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Position&lt;/em&gt;: Head of project.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Recipients&lt;/em&gt;: HELVETIA COMPAÑÍA SUIZA, S.A. DE SEGUROS Y REASEGUROS. 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work carried out corresponds to the optimization of the procedures for downloading and using weather forecast data and AEMET alerts at a municipal scale, and has consisted in summary of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The analysis and implementation of a program for the realization of web scraping of the data of interest to the AEMET related to weather forecasting and alerts at the municipal level, as well as its transformation, adaptation and persistence in a database for its subsequent exploitation and internal diffusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tools used in the development of the works have been: R programming language, SQLite database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/2021-helvetia-aemet-captura.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis and diagnosis of the needs for bus shelters and proposals for improving accessibility and road safety at public transport stops in the province of Seville, excluding the sphere of competence of the Seville Metropolitan Transport Consortium. 015/2021- SERV.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2021-paradasbus-sevilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2021-paradasbus-sevilla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Position&lt;/em&gt;: Head of project.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Recipients&lt;/em&gt;: Territorial Delegation of the Regional Ministry of Development, Infrastructure and Territory Planning in Seville. Government of Andalusia. 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work carried out corresponds to the identification, analysis and diagnosis of regular public transport stops for general use in the province of Seville, excluding the sphere of competence of the Public Transport Consortium of the Province of Seville, determining for each stop if there is a marquee and /or information post at that point, equipment and, if so, the state of conservation and the specific maintenance needs required. Likewise, the analysis of the accessibility and road safety of the stops is included, and they have schematically consisted of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification and determination of the points where the regular transport lines for general use of the Junta de Andalucía stop in the province of Seville within the territorial scope of the Territorial Delegation of the Ministry of Development, Infrastructure and Territorial Planning In sevilla. (1029 points).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elaboration of Work Plan and File Model: Field, Diagnosis and Proposal File Model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Field work to verify the existence and analysis of the characteristics and condition of the equipment, accessibility and road safety.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing of Diagnosis Memory, Evaluation of the situation of the stops and Proposal of actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of database, GIS project and report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The GIS tools and formats used in the development of the work have been: SQLite database, Geopackage format, desktop GIS QGIS and QField for field work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/2021-ParadasBus-Sevilla.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Technical Assistance for updating and digitizing the technical files of thirteen state-owned dams of the Júcar River Basin.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2020-typsa-chj-archivopresas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2020-typsa-chj-archivopresas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Position&lt;/em&gt;: Jefe de proyecto.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Recipients&lt;/em&gt;: TYPSA for the Júcar River Basin Authority. 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work carried out corresponds to the analysis, design and development of the XWPFPresas computer application that supports the management of the Technical Files of Dams of the Júcar River Basin Authority, and which in summary have consisted of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis, design and development of a desktop application for the management of the Technical Files of CHJ Dams with the following characteristics:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQL Server 2016 database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft .NET technology with C# language and EF and WPF frameworks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Processes of transformation, debugging and massive data loading of the technical files of 23 dams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drafting of User Manual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/2020-TYPSA-CHJ-ArchivoPresas.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer technical assistance in the deployment, management and maintenance of servers, OGC map services and WebGIS viewer for the public exhibition of the review of floodplains of the Júcar River Basin District.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2020-webgis-jucar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2020-webgis-jucar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Position&lt;/em&gt;: Head of project.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Recipients&lt;/em&gt;: TYPSA for Júcar River Basin Authority. 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work carried out has consisted in summary of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain registration revision-snczi-jucar.es.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux VPS Server Configuration and Deployment of Base Applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GIS Server Configuration: Geoserver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publication of OGC Services: WFS / WCS / WMS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adaptation, Deployment, Configuration and Personalization of Basic WebGIS Client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monthly maintenance for thirteen months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/2020-WebGIS-Jucar.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote sensing with R.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/talk/2019-teledeteccion_sevillar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/talk/2019-teledeteccion_sevillar/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/RStudio_SevillaR_Teledeteccion_con_R.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delineation of the water surface and its evolution after the floods of the September 13, 2019 in Vega Baja of the Segura River using remote sensing techniques.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2019-vegabaja-segura/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2019-vegabaja-segura/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Position&lt;/em&gt;: Head of project.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Recipients&lt;/em&gt;: TYPSA. 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work carried out has consisted in summary of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acquisition of COSMO-SkyMed satellite image of 09/14/2019 (StripMap HIMAGE) of the Vega Baja del Río Segura.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treatment of 11 images from the Sentinel-1, Sentinel-2, PlanetScope and SkyMed satellites between September 10 and 29 in the Vega Baja del Río Segura (696 Km2), through correction, calculation of indices, thresholding and vectorization of flooded surfaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report writing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/2019-VegaBaja-Segura.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of the evolution of the flooded surface of the Doñana lagoons between November 2017 and November 2018 [CU(PH)-6134].</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2019-lagunas-donana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2019-lagunas-donana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Position&lt;/em&gt;: Head of project.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Recipients&lt;/em&gt;: Guadalquivir River Basin Authority. Hydrologic Planning Office. 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work carried out corresponds to the update, until November 2018, of the series of data to monitor the evolution of the flooded surface and vegetation in the Doñana lake-type water bodies, derived from remote sensing, and more specifically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determination of the frequency of flooding and analysis of the evolution of the extension of the water surface in the study period, from the water index (MNDWI), derived from satellite images and its relationship with the rainfall data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evolution of vegetation from the vegetation index (NDVI) derived from satellite images for the study period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images from the Sentinel 2 satellite have been used, and an image has been selected for each of the months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/2019-Lagunas-Donana.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geometric-topological debugging of geographic data with R.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/talk/2019-depurgeo_sevillar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/talk/2019-depurgeo_sevillar/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/2019-DepuRGeo-SevillaR.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatio-Temporal Patterns and Predictive Models of the use of Sevici&#39;s bicycles.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/talk/2018-sevici_sevillar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/talk/2018-sevici_sevillar/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/SevillaR_20180605.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatio-Temporal patterns of the use of Sevici&#39;s bicycles.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/talk/2018-sevici_databeersvq4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/talk/2018-sevici_databeersvq4/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/DatabeerSVQ4_Sevici.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Bike - Sevilla: Spatio-Temporal Patterns and Predictive Models of the use of Sevici&#39;s bicycles.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2018-tfm-sevici/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2018-tfm-sevici/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Position&lt;/em&gt;: Author.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Recipients&lt;/em&gt;: University of Seville. 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From open data published by the Sevici’s management company and compiled by the Universities of Huelva and Seville for a year, the temporal, spatial and spatio-temporal patterns of the use of Sevici&amp;rsquo;s bicycles are identified. The results confirm their effective use as a means of transport (alternative) in daily activities and also, intuit the preferred functional role in the urban structure of the different areas in which the stations are located.&lt;br /&gt;
Predictive models of the use of bicycles have also been built, for short-range time horizons (15min, 30min, 1h, 4h, 8h and 24h). In total, 1813 models have been estimated, seven for each of the stations, all, regression models with elasticnet regularization. The results of their testing have shown a very good predictive capacity, with RMSE (root mean square error) of 17.6 on average (percentage of available bikes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/JeronimoCarranza2/TFM-Sevici&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/img/2018-TFM-Sevici.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in QGIS.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/talk/2017-rinqgis_sevillarusers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/talk/2017-rinqgis_sevillarusers/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
