<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jerónimo Carranza Carranza</title>
    <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jerónimo Carranza Carranza</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Jerónimo Carranza Carranza</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Bike - Sevilla: Spatio-Temporal Patterns and Predictive Models of the use of Sevici&#39;s bicycles.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2018-tfm-sevici/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2018-tfm-sevici/</guid>
      <description>Position: Author.
Recipients: University of Seville. 2018.
From open data published by the Sevici’s management company and compiled by the Universities of Huelva and Seville for a year, the temporal, spatial and spatio-temporal patterns of the use of Sevici&amp;rsquo;s bicycles are identified. The results confirm their effective use as a means of transport (alternative) in daily activities and also, intuit the preferred functional role in the urban structure of the different areas in which the stations are located.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geographic Information System of Groundwater Quality in the Guadalquivir River.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2011-brocal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2011-brocal/</guid>
      <description>Position: Head of project.
Recipients: Guadalquivir River Basin Authority. 2011.
In the framework of the project of exploitation of the quality control network of the groundwater of the Guadalquivir Basin was developed the Brocal system. It is a Geographic Information System in a web environment that supports both information management tasks and its alphanumeric, graphic and geographic exploitation. Brocal is integrated by a Java application (J2EE) with three-layer architecture and webgis client, an OGC map server and a database with spatial support:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SaneaCLM: Information System of Sanitation of Urban Wastewater Treatment in Castilla–La Mancha.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2015-saneaclm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2015-saneaclm/</guid>
      <description>Position: Head of project.
Recipients: Water Agency of Castilla – La Mancha. 2015.
In the framework of the project &amp;ldquo;Control and Diagnosis of Urban Wastewater Treatment Plants in Castilla-La Mancha, 2011-2015&amp;rdquo;, the design, development and implementation of a J2EE software application, called SaneaCLM, has been carried out for the information management of urban wastewater treatment plants (EDAR) and graphical, geographic and alphanumeric exploitation of their structural and analytical data. SaneaCLM is based on the following technologies:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development and Implementation of a Geographical Information System of the Ewaso Ng&#39;Iro South River Basin.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2014-engiros/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2014-engiros/</guid>
      <description>Position: Technical Coordinator.
Recipients: Government of Kenya. Ministry of Regional Development Authorities (MoRDA). 2014.
The project aims at the design, development and implementation of a corporate Geographic Information System of the Regional Development Authority of Ewaso Ng&amp;rsquo;iro South (ENSDA), with destination in the Office of the Headquarters of the ENSDA in Narok. Support and installation of all necessary software and hardware is provided. The activities developed include:
 Analysis and Design</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Data Infrastructure of TYPSA Group.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2014-idetypsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2014-idetypsa/</guid>
      <description>Position: Head of project.
Recipients: TYPSA Group. 2014.
The Spatial Data Infrastructure of TYPSA Group (IDETypsa) is an R+D+i project developed by the Department of Territorial Information of Andalusia that aims to increase the efficiency in the access, use, exploitation and dissemination of geographic information within the Group. IDETypsa has been developed entirely with open source free software components, among others:
 BD: PostgreSQL – PostGIS GIS Server: Geoserver Print Server: MapFishPrint WebGIS Client: TYPterraMap with ExtJS and OpenLayers  Publication</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>