<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent Projects on Jerónimo Carranza Carranza</title>
    <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent Projects on Jerónimo Carranza Carranza</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Jerónimo Carranza Carranza</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PROVISION OF INFORMATION ON SEVERAL STATISTICAL ACTIVITIES OF P.E.C.A. 2013- 2020. Lot 3. Databases of registrations of Andalusian Companies, December 2018 / January 2021.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2022-bormes-ieca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2022-bormes-ieca/</guid>
      <description>Position: Head of project.
Recipients: Institute of Statistics and Cartography of Andalusia. 2022.
The work carried out has consisted in summary of the provision in electronic format, in databases, of the registry acts related to the constitution, increase and reduction of capital, disbursement of passive dividends, transformation, split, merger, dissolution, extinction and different phases bankruptcy of Andalusian commercial companies published in the Official Gazette of the Mercantile Registry (BORME), as well as the CIF and CNAE of said entities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer technical assistance for the creation of a open spatial database to store and manage the data compiled in the catalog of hydraulic sanitation infrastructures of the Comunidad Valenciana.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2022-saneacv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2022-saneacv/</guid>
      <description>Position: Head of project.
Recipients: TYPSA for the Department of Agriculture, Rural Development, Climate Emergencies and Ecological Transition. Government of Valencia. 2022.
The works carried out have consisted schematically of:
 Definition and implementation of the data model of the Catalog of Hydraulic Infrastructures for Sanitation of the Valencian Community as a Postgresql / Postgis database. Implementation of the model, in tests, as an alternative or exchange, in SQLite / Geopackage database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis and diagnosis of the needs for bus shelters and proposals for improving accessibility and road safety at public transport stops in the province of Seville, excluding the sphere of competence of the Seville Metropolitan Transport Consortium. 015/2021- SERV.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2021-paradasbus-sevilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2021-paradasbus-sevilla/</guid>
      <description>Position: Head of project.
Recipients: Territorial Delegation of the Regional Ministry of Development, Infrastructure and Territory Planning in Seville. Government of Andalusia. 2021.
The work carried out corresponds to the identification, analysis and diagnosis of regular public transport stops for general use in the province of Seville, excluding the sphere of competence of the Public Transport Consortium of the Province of Seville, determining for each stop if there is a marquee and /or information post at that point, equipment and, if so, the state of conservation and the specific maintenance needs required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer technical assistance in the deployment, management and maintenance of servers, OGC map services and WebGIS viewer for the public exhibition of the review of floodplains of the Júcar River Basin District.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2020-webgis-jucar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2020-webgis-jucar/</guid>
      <description>Posición: Head of project.
Destinatarios: TYPSA for Júcar River Basin Authority. 2020.
The work carried out has consisted in summary of:
 Domain registration revision-snczi-jucar.es. Linux VPS Server Configuration and Deployment of Base Applications. GIS Server Configuration: Geoserver. Publication of OGC Services: WFS / WCS / WMS. Adaptation, Deployment, Configuration and Personalization of Basic WebGIS Client. Monthly maintenance for thirteen months.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delineation of the water surface and its evolution after the floods of the September 13, 2019 in Vega Baja of the Segura River using remote sensing techniques.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2019-vegabaja-segura/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2019-vegabaja-segura/</guid>
      <description>Posición: Head of project.
Destinatarios: TYPSA. 2019.
The work carried out has consisted in summary of:
 Acquisition of COSMO-SkyMed satellite image of 09/14/2019 (StripMap HIMAGE) of the Vega Baja del Río Segura. Treatment of 11 images from the Sentinel-1, Sentinel-2, PlanetScope and SkyMed satellites between September 10 and 29 in the Vega Baja del Río Segura (696 Km2), through correction, calculation of indices, thresholding and vectorization of flooded surfaces. Report writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of the evolution of the flooded surface of the Doñana lagoons between November 2017 and November 2018 [CU(PH)-6134].</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2019-lagunas-donana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2019-lagunas-donana/</guid>
      <description>Posición: Head of project.
Destinatarios: Guadalquivir River Basin Authority. Hydrologic Planning Office. 2019.
The work carried out corresponds to the update, until November 2018, of the series of data to monitor the evolution of the flooded surface and vegetation in the Doñana lake-type water bodies, derived from remote sensing, and more specifically:
 Determination of the frequency of flooding and analysis of the evolution of the extension of the water surface in the study period, from the water index (MNDWI), derived from satellite images and its relationship with the rainfall data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Bike - Sevilla: Spatio-Temporal Patterns and Predictive Models of the use of Sevici&#39;s bicycles.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2018-tfm-sevici/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2018-tfm-sevici/</guid>
      <description>Position: Author.
Recipients: University of Seville. 2018.
From open data published by the Sevici’s management company and compiled by the Universities of Huelva and Seville for a year, the temporal, spatial and spatio-temporal patterns of the use of Sevici&amp;rsquo;s bicycles are identified. The results confirm their effective use as a means of transport (alternative) in daily activities and also, intuit the preferred functional role in the urban structure of the different areas in which the stations are located.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geographic Information System of Groundwater Quality in the Guadalquivir River.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2011-brocal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2011-brocal/</guid>
      <description>Position: Head of project.
Recipients: Guadalquivir River Basin Authority. 2011.
In the framework of the project of exploitation of the quality control network of the groundwater of the Guadalquivir Basin was developed the Brocal system. It is a Geographic Information System in a web environment that supports both information management tasks and its alphanumeric, graphic and geographic exploitation. Brocal is integrated by a Java application (J2EE) with three-layer architecture and webgis client, an OGC map server and a database with spatial support:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SaneaCLM: Information System of Sanitation of Urban Wastewater Treatment in Castilla–La Mancha.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2015-saneaclm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2015-saneaclm/</guid>
      <description>Position: Head of project.
Recipients: Water Agency of Castilla – La Mancha. 2015.
In the framework of the project &amp;ldquo;Control and Diagnosis of Urban Wastewater Treatment Plants in Castilla-La Mancha, 2011-2015&amp;rdquo;, the design, development and implementation of a J2EE software application, called SaneaCLM, has been carried out for the information management of urban wastewater treatment plants (EDAR) and graphical, geographic and alphanumeric exploitation of their structural and analytical data. SaneaCLM is based on the following technologies:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development and Implementation of a Geographical Information System of the Ewaso Ng&#39;Iro South River Basin.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2014-engiros/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2014-engiros/</guid>
      <description>Position: Technical Coordinator.
Recipients: Government of Kenya. Ministry of Regional Development Authorities (MoRDA). 2014.
The project aims at the design, development and implementation of a corporate Geographic Information System of the Regional Development Authority of Ewaso Ng&amp;rsquo;iro South (ENSDA), with destination in the Office of the Headquarters of the ENSDA in Narok. Support and installation of all necessary software and hardware is provided. The activities developed include:
 Analysis and Design</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Data Infrastructure of TYPSA Group.</title>
      <link>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2014-idetypsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JeronimoCarranza.github.io/project/2014-idetypsa/</guid>
      <description>Position: Head of project.
Recipients: TYPSA Group. 2014.
The Spatial Data Infrastructure of TYPSA Group (IDETypsa) is an R+D+i project developed by the Department of Territorial Information of Andalusia that aims to increase the efficiency in the access, use, exploitation and dissemination of geographic information within the Group. IDETypsa has been developed entirely with open source free software components, among others:
 BD: PostgreSQL – PostGIS GIS Server: Geoserver Print Server: MapFishPrint WebGIS Client: TYPterraMap with ExtJS and OpenLayers  Publication</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>